DEJAN ĐENIĆ

+381641582898 | dejandjenic@gmail.com | Belgrade,Serbia www.dejandjenic.com , medium.com/@dejandjenic

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Productive, intelligent, and highly self-motivated Engineering Manager and Software Architect with over 20 years of experience in developing applications and utilizing .NET technologies. Proven track record in leading backend teams, designing microservices, and architecting cloud-native solutions on GCP and Azure. Contributor to open-source projects including GraphQL and Testcontainers libraries. Author of XWorkflows, Sagas, and GenesysSSG open-source libraries. Regularly publishes articles on technology and development.

EXPERIENCE

Engineering Manager, Software Architect

2022 - Present

InterVenture (Serbia), AspenDental (USA)

- Leading backend team and designing microservices for the Digital case management subdomain.
- Designing and developing inhouse DICOM solution.
- Designing and developing microservices for public website -> core system integration.
- Early work on setting up Identity server system at AspenDental.

Lead Backend Engineer, Director level

2021 - 2022

BlackRock (USA)

- Developed financial products for Private Equity Investment.
- Heavily involved in product performance optimization before product launch

Senior Software Developer, Backend Team Lead

2019 - 2021

InterVenture (Serbia), Redbox (USA)

- Designed architecture for new on-demand services.
- Led the team in the development, maintenance, and monitoring of microservices for Redbox systems.
- Implemented a new identity stack with IdentityServer and data migration to the cloud.

Software Architect, Chief Information Officer

2013 - 2019

Companywall (Serbia, UK, Slovenia, Croatia)

- Designed and developed the company's ERP system.
- Developed contact center applications and mobile applications.
- Implemented a financial portal and managed IT operations.

Previous Work Experience

2001 - 2013

Various roles in different companies

- E-Banking solution for SAGA (Serbia)
- Job portals in Russia, Slovenia, Serbia
- Retail portal in Iran
- ERP, CRM, Call center, ...

SKILLS

- Languages: .NET Core, C#, SQL, ASP.NET, MVC, Python, JavaScript (React, Blazor), XML
- Cloud Platforms: GCP, Azure, AWS
- Databases: SQL Server, MySQL, MongoDB, BigQuery, Firestore, DynamoDB
- Tools & Frameworks: GraphQL, Docker, Kubernetes, Amazon Web Services, LINQ, Entity Framework, SOLR, Elasticsearch, Windows Forms
- Frontend: React, Blazor
- Methodologies: SCRUM, Kanban

OPEN-SOURCE CONTRIBUTION

- Contributor to GraphQL library and Testcontainers library.
- Author of XWorkflows (workflow management library), Sagas (distributed orchestrations library), and GenesysSSG (dotnet static site generator).

EDUCATION & CERTIFICATIONS

- Courses and self-education (2001)
- MCSE & MCSD courses at Guidance Yugoslavia (2000-2001)
- Elementary school, V Belgrade Gymnasium, Law study for 2 years (2000)

PERSONAL PROJECTS

- Great Hack Hackaton project OpenAI, .net 8, Cloud Native https://github.com/dejandjenic/Hackaton8
- https://github.com/dejandjenic